foreign
[Music]
what is the truth about over-the-counter
Anti-aging products which costed a
billion dollar industry there is a
psychological effect from spending more
wrote a team of dermatologists but don't
be seduced by fancy packaging and high
prices many products advertise dramatic
results that are frequently exaggerated
and misleading and are rarely
scientifically supported an independent
product testing Institute questioned the
efficacy of anti-aging creams generally
find that beneficial effects could only
be picked up using sensitive instruments
without becoming clinically or
noticeably detectable they suggest these
products may not work any better than
typical moisturizers
cross-sectional studies of Chinese and
British women further those who
regularly use facial moisturizers were
guessed to be about two years younger
than those the same age who didn't
however a third larger Dutch study did
not and regardless snapshot and time
studies can never establish cause and
effect
studies on moisturizers are limited but
they can improve the appearance of dry
skin which can otherwise look discolored
flaky and rough moisturizers can hydrate
the skin and may reduce the appearance
of Fine Lines by 15 to 20 percent called
the oldest tricked in the Cosmetic
industry but may not do anything to
treat the underlying cause
whether a facial Foundation or night
cream or anti-aging serum the
formulations of most skin products are
basically a moisturizer combined with
purported active ingredients for
marketing appeal
which ingredients are actually active
anti-aging agents I'll give you a hint
up to 90 of visible aging of someone's
face is due to sun exposure from an
anti-aging standpoint the most
biologically active ingredient in skin
products is sunscreen
consider the most important thing to
maintain youthful skin is the daily
application of sunscreen and other
protective measures like wearing a hat
all other things you can do for your
skin pale in comparison especially for
those with pale skin
to prevent skin cancer the American
Academy of Dermatology recommends
sunscreen with a SPF of 30 or higher but
an SPF of 15 can prevent skin aging how
do we know because it's been put to the
test 900 adults were randomized to years
of daily sunscreen use or to continue
their own discretionary use it was
considered unethical to withhold
protection by giving people Placebo
sunscreen in the end 77 of the
recommended daily sunscreen group were
applying sunscreen at least three to
four days per week compared with 33 in
the discretionary use group would that
be enough of a difference to make a
difference
yes there were significantly less skin
Aging in the instructed daily use group
in fact they suffered no detectable
increase in skin aging over about 4.5
year study the researchers concluded
daily sunscreen use protects against
skin aging
although sunscreens are primarily
intended to prevent further facial aging
rather than reverse photo damage already
done some in the daily sunscreen use
group did show an improvement in skin
texture the results are all the more
striking given the control group was
told to continue to use sunscreen and
hats whenever they thought necessary
suggesting people are poor judges or
planners for excess UV exposure when
left to their own devices so a daily
facial moisturizer with an SPF 15 and it
is recommended even if it's cloudy or
raining outside considered the gold
standard for anti-aging skin care daily
use of sunscreens in the daytime and
retinoids at night
retinoids oh cover them next
[Music]
foreign